Ruth Krauss Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
- Series II: Children's Literature, undated, 1947-1989
  - A Hole Is to Dig
    - Sketches by Maurice Sendak, undated (Box 8:, Folder 271)
    - Cover sketches by Maurice Sendak, undated (Box 8:, Folder 272)
    - Paste-ups with sketches by Maurice Sendak [Note: Fragile!], undated (Box 8:, Folder 273)
    - Photocopied illustrations [negative], undated (Box 8:, Folder 273a)
    - Single dummy pages, undated (Box 8:, Folder 274)
    - Rough first dummy, undated (Box 8:, Folder 275)
    - Second dummy (?), 1950 November 2 (Box 8:, Folder 276)
    - Early dummy, small, undated (Box 8:, Folder 277)
    - Early dummies, medium, undated (Box 8:, Folder 278)
    - Early dummy, large, undated (Box 8:, Folder 279)
    - Late dummies, medium, undated (Box 8:, Folder 280)
    - Late dummies, large, undated (Box 8:, Folder 281)
    - Late dummy, oversize, undated (Box 17:, Folder 636)
    - Paste-up dummy and copy (images not used in book), undated (Box 8:, Folder 282)
    - Notes on illustrations, undated (Box 8:, Folder 283)
    - Advertisement, 1953 December 13 (Box 8:, Folder 284)
    - Related print matter, 1963 March - 1985 November (Box 8:, Folder 285)
    - Parody booklet, A Hole is What You Need this Book Like in Your Head, undated (Box 8:, Folder 286)
  - "Hooray for Everyday!" (poster), related materials, undated (Box 8:, Folder 287)
  - "Hooray for Little Rainbows in the Rain Rain Rain" [tss], undated (Box 8:, Folder 288)
  - "Houses"
    - Notes, undated (Box 8:, Folder 289)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 8:, Folder 290)
    - Large dummy, undated (Box 8:, Folder 291)
  - How to Make an Earthquake
    - Notes, undated (Box 9:, Folder 292)
    - Undated typescripts and manuscripts (Box 9:, Folder 293)
    - "Discards" [tss], undated (Box 9:, Folder 293a)
    - "Final" typescript [copy], undated (Box 9:, Folder 294)
    - Final typescript with printer's instructions, ca. 1954 July (Box 9:, Folder 295)
    - Arrangement and instructions to printer, undated (Box 9:, Folder 296)
    - List of heads, undated (Box 9:, Folder 297)
    - Paste-ups and copies, undated (Box 9:, Folder 298)
  - I Can Fly
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 9:, Folder 299)
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 9:, Folder 300)
    - "Bank St./Golden Book Original" [tss and copy], undated (Box 9:, Folder 301)
    - Abridged version [tss], 1980 December 4 (Box 9:, Folder 302)
    - Dummy fragments, undated (Box 9:, Folder 303)
    - Dummies, undated (Box 9:, Folder 304)
    - Dummy, abridged version, ca. 1980 December 3 (Box 9:, Folder 305)
  - I Want to Paint My Bathroom Blue
    - Version 1 [tss], undated (Box 9:, Folder 306)
    - Version 2 [tss and copies], undated (Box 9:, Folder 307)
    - Version 3 "Final?" [tss], undated (Box 9:, Folder 308)
    - Version 4 [tss copy], undated (Box 9:, Folder 309)
    - Typescript, copy sent to Maurice Sendak, undated (Box 9:, Folder 310)
    - Clean typescripts, undated (Box 9:, Folder 311)
    - Small illustrations by Krauss, undated (Box 9:, Folder 312)
    - Sketches by Crockett Johnson, undated (Box 9:, Folder 313)
    - Sketches by Krauss, undated (Box 9:, Folder 314)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 9:, Folder 315)
    - Large dummy, undated (Box 9:, Folder 316)
  - I Wouldn't Want to be a Pancake (unpublished)
    - Alternate endings [tss], undated (Box 9:, Folder 317)
    - Dummy, undated (Box 9:, Folder 318)
  - "I Write It"
    - Undated manuscripts (Box 9:, Folder 319)
    - Undated typescripts (Box 9:, Folder 320)
    - Typescript with notes to artist, undated (Box 9:, Folder 321)
    - Typescript, 1966 August 9 (Box 9:, Folder 322)
    - Typescripts (2), 1966 September 3 (Box 9:, Folder 323)
    - Typescript, 1966 September 15 (Box 9:, Folder 324)
    - Typescript, 1966 October 23 (Box 9:, Folder 325)
    - Typescript and copy, [1966] December 29 (Box 9:, Folder 326)
    - Typescripts, 1967 January (Box 9:, Folder 327)
    - Manuscript, [1967] January 9 (Box 9:, Folder 328)
    - Typescript, 1967 January 12 (Box 9:, Folder 329)
    - Typescript, 1967 January 15 (Box 9:, Folder 330)
    - Typescript, 1967 January 15 (Box 9:, Folder 331)
    - Typescript, 1968 October (Box 9:, Folder 332)
    - Short verson for poster, undated (Box 9:, Folder 333)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 9:, Folder 334)
    - Jacket text and biography, undated (Box 9:, Folder 335)
    - Small dummies, undated (Box 9:, Folder 336)
    - Large sketch dummy, undated (Box 9:, Folder 337)
    - Large dummy, "3rd from Last," and copy, undated (Box 9:, Folder 338)
  - ["I'll Be Grown Up So Long When I'm Grown"]
    - Typescripts and manuscripts, undated (Box 10:, Folder 339)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 10:, Folder 340)
  - I'll Be You and You Be Me
    - Notes, ca. 1953-1954 (Box 10:, Folder 341)
    - Partial typescripts and manuscripts, undated (Box 10:, Folder 342)
    - Early typescripts, undated (Box 10:, Folder 343)
    - Early compilation [tss], undated (Box 10:, Folder 343a)
    - Blocked typescripts, undated (Box 10:, Folder 344)
    - "Final Arrangement,", ca. 1953-1954 (Box 10:, Folder 345)
    - Printer's typescript and copy, ca. 1954 April 28 (Box 10:, Folder 346)
    - Sketches by Krauss, undated (Box 10:, Folder 347)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 10:, Folder 348)
    - Partial dummies, undated (Box 10:, Folder 349)
    - Partial paste-up dummy and copy, undated (Box 10:, Folder 350)
    - Small dummy, undated (Box 10:, Folder 350a)
    - Large dummy A, undated (Box 10:, Folder 351)
    - Large dummy B, undated (Box 10:, Folder 352)
    - Notes and sketches by Krauss, undated (Box 10:, Folder 353)
    - Galleys, undated (Box OS:, Folder 658)
  - Is This You?
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 10:, Folder 354)
    - Partial typescripts, undated (Box 10:, Folder 355)
    - Sketches by Krauss and Crockett Johnson, undated (Box 10:, Folder 356)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 10:, Folder 357)
    - Layout sketch by Crockett Johnson, undated (Box 10:, Folder 358)
    - Small dummy, undated (Box 10:, Folder 359)
    - Large dummies, undated (Box 10:, Folder 360)
    - Illustrated mock-up dummy, undated (Box 10:, Folder 361)
    - Oversize illustrated dummy (partial), undated (Box 17:, Folder 637)
    - Notes [Some notes by Krauss, others by Crockett Johnson.], undated (Box 10:, Folder 362)
  - The Kitten and the Lion
    - Sketches by Krauss, ca. 1966 (Box 10:, Folder 363)
    - Small dummy, ca. 1966 (Box 10:, Folder 364)
    - Large dummy, ca. 1966 (Box 10:, Folder 365)
    - Discarded pages for large dummy, ca. 1966 (Box 10:, Folder 366)
  - Little Boat Lighter than a Cork
    - Early "Lion" versions [tss], undated (Box 10:, Folder 367)
    - Intermediate versions [tss], undated (Box 10:, Folder 368)
    - Late versions [tss and mss], undated (Box 10:, Folder 369)
    - Dialogue versions [tss], undated (Box 10:, Folder 370)
    - Annotated copies of typescripts, undated (Box 10:, Folder 371)
    - Unused insert page [tss, mss, and sketches], undated (Box 10:, Folder 372)
    - "Last Version" [tss and mss], undated (Box 10:, Folder 373)
    - Typescript with printer's instructons, undated (Box 10:, Folder 374)
    - Typescript copy with printer's instructions, 1971 March 27 (Box 10:, Folder 375)
    - Drawing by Krauss, ca. 1971 March 27 (Box 10:, Folder 376)
    - Annotated illustration, undated (Box 10:, Folder 377)
    - Krauss's comments on preliminary dummy, ca. 1972 March (Box 10:, Folder 378)
    - Dummy fragments (4), undated (Box 10:, Folder 379)
    - Paste-up dummy fragment A and copy, undated (Box 10:, Folder 380)
    - Paste-up dummy fragment B and copy, undated (Box 10:, Folder 381)
    - Copy of "Esther's Little Boat", undated (Box 10:, Folder 382)
    - Paste-up extras, undated (Box 10:, Folder 383)
    - Small dummies, undated (Box 10:, Folder 384)
    - Illustrated paste-up dummy and copy, undated (Box 10:, Folder 385)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 11:, Folder 386)
    - Layout drawing and related materials, undated (Box 11:, Folder 387)
    - Cut galleys, ca. 1978 (Box 11:, Folder 388)
    - Large proofs, ca. 1978 (Box 17:, Folder 638)
    - Overlays, undated (Box 17:, Folder 639)
    - Cardstock broadsides, undated (Box 11:, Folder 389)
    - Promotional bookmark, Magic Circle Press, undated (Box 11:, Folder 390)
    - Brochures and catalogues, ca. 1978 (Box 11:, Folder 391)
    - Dust jackets, undated (Box 11:, Folder 392)
    - Musical program, undated (Box 11:, Folder 392a)
  - ["The Little Boy and His Mother"] (unpublished) [tss], undated (Box 11:, Folder 393)
  - The Little Cloud in the Sky, "Rough" [tss, mss, and sketches], undated (Box 11:, Folder 394)
  - ["Little Girl and Little Stream"] (unpublished), [tss and mss], undated (Box 11:, Folder 395)
  - The Little King, the Little Queen, the Little Monster
    - Notes, undated (Box 11:, Folder 396)
    - "Little Queen," first treatment, [no year] March 10 (Box 11:, Folder 397)
    - Title page, undated (Box 11:, Folder 398)
    - "The Little Queen," early versions, [tss and mss], undated (Box 11:, Folder 399)
    - Later versions [tss], [no year] December 27 (Box 11:, Folder 400)
    - "The Little Monster," partial typescript, undated (Box 11:, Folder 401)
    - "The Little Monster," Version A [tss], undated (Box 11:, Folder 402)
    - "The Little Monster," Version B [tss], undated (Box 11:, Folder 403)
    - "The Little Monster," Version C [copy], undated (Box 11:, Folder 404)
    - "The Little Monster," published version [tss], undated (Box 11:, Folder 405)
    - "The Little Monster," "New Version" [tss], undated (Box 11:, Folder 406)
    - ["The Little Boy"], unpublished [tss], undated (Box 11:, Folder 407)
    - "The Little Woman," sketches by Krauss, undated (Box 11:, Folder 408)
    - "The Little Woman," dummies, undated (Box 11:, Folder 409)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 11:, Folder 410)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 11:, Folder 411)
    - Partial paste-up dummy A, extra text, undated (Box 11:, Folder 412)
    - Partial paste-up dummy B and copy, undated (Box 11:, Folder 413)
    - Partial paste-up dummy C and copy, undated (Box 11:, Folder 414)
    - ["The Little Monster, the Little Child, the Little Dog"] (unpublished), dummy, undated (Box 11:, Folder 415)
    - "The Little King, the Little Queen," dummy and copoy, undated (Box 11:, Folder 416)
    - "The Little Monster," dummies, undated (Box 11:, Folder 417)
    - Overlays (incomplete), ca. 1966 (Box 11:, Folder 418)
    - Partial galley, ca. 1966 (Box 17:, Folder 640)
    - Mock-up, ca. 1966 (Box 18:, Folder 650)
    - Mechanicals, ca. 1966 (Box 17:, Folder 641)
    - Book cover, ca. 1966 (Box 11:, Folder 419)
    - Krauss's photocopies, undated (Box 11:, Folder 420)
    - Catalogs, 1969-1973 (Box 11:, Folder 421)
    - "The Little Computer" [tss], undated (Box 11:, Folder 421a)
  - Little Love Poems for Little People [tss], undated (Box 11, Folder 421b)
  - Little Newspaper Elephant (unpublished), layout sketch, undated (Box 11:, Folder 422)
  - "Little One" (unpublished)[mss, notes, layout sketches], undated (Box 11:, Folder 423)
  - "The Little Queen" (unpublished story)
    - Summary and discussion [tss], ca. 1958 (Box 12:, Folder 424)
    - Notes, ca. 1958 (Box 12:, Folder 425)
    - Manuscript A, ca. 1958 (Box 12:, Folder 426)
    - Manuscript B, ca. 1958 (Box 12:, Folder 427)
    - Annotated typescripts and manuscripts, ca. 1958 (Box 12:, Folder 428)
    - Typescripts and manuscripts, [1958]January 4 (Box 12:, Folder 429)
    - Comments, [1958] January 25 (Box 12:, Folder 430)
    - Typescript, [1958] January 26 (Box 12:, Folder 431)
    - Sketches by Krauss, ca. 1958 (Box 12:, Folder 432)
    - Illustrations by Maurice Sendak, ca. 1958 (Box 12:, Folder 433)
    - Oversize illustrations by Maurice Sendak, ca. 1958 (Box 18:, Folder 651)
    - Comments by Krauss on Sendak's illustrations, ca. 1958 (Box 12:, Folder 434)
    - Layout sketches, ca. 1958 (Box 12:, Folder 435)
  - ["Lucky Story"] (unpublished)
    - "Very First Version" [tss], 1969 (Box 12:, Folder 436)
    - "Good Luck Story" [tss], 1969 May (Box 12:, Folder 437)
    - Revised typescript and copy, undated (Box 12:, Folder 438)
  - "The Magic Hole" (unpublished) [mss], undated (Box 12:, Folder 440)
  - Mama, I Wish I Was Snow
    - Treatment, undated (Box 12:, Folder 441)
    - Undated manuscripts (Box 12:, Folder 442)
    - Undated typescripts (Box 12:, Folder 443)
    - Typescript, 1960 June 10 (Box 12:, Folder 444)
    - Typescript, 1960 June 20 (Box 12:, Folder 445)
    - Typescript, 1960 June 26 (Box 12:, Folder 446)
    - Typescript, 1970 July 3 - 4 (Box 12:, Folder 447)
    - Typescript, 1960 July 13 (Box 12:, Folder 448)
    - Typescript, 1960 September 24 (Box 12:, Folder 449)
    - Typescript, 1960 December (Box 12:, Folder 450)
    - Typescript, 1960 December 9 (Box 12:, Folder 451)
    - Typescript, 1960 December 11 (Box 12:, Folder 452)
    - Typescript, 1961 January 19 (Box 12:, Folder 453)
    - Typescript, 1961 February 26 (Box 12:, Folder 454)
    - Typescript, 1961 March 11 (Box 12:, Folder 455)
    - Typescript, 1961 March 27 (Box 12:, Folder 456)
    - "Final" [tss and copy], ca. 1961 (Box 12:, Folder 457)
    - Typescript for typist and typist's typescripts, ca. 1961 (Box 12:, Folder 458)
    - Typescript with printer's instructions, 1961 (Box 12:, Folder 459)
    - Layout sketches (by Ellen Raskin?), ca. February 1962 (Box 12:, Folder 461)
    - Small dummy, ca. 1960-61 (Box 12:, Folder 462)
    - Small paste-up dummy, ca. 1960-1961 (Box 12:, Folder 463)
    - Large paste-up dummy and copy, ca. 1960-1961 (Box 12:, Folder 464)
    - Catalogs, 1962 (Box 12:, Folder 465)
    - Reviews and clippings, ca. 1962 (Box 12:, Folder 466)
  - Meese Mice (unpublished)
    - Typescript, undated (Box 12:, Folder 467)
    - Dummy and copy, undated (Box 12:, Folder 468)
  - Monkey Day
    - Notes, undated (Box 12:, Folder 469)
    - Typescript and copy, undated (Box 12:, Folder 470)
    - Dummy and copy, undated (Box 12:, Folder 471)
    - Galley, undated (Box OS:, Folder 659)
    - Paste-up dummy and copies, undated (Box 12:, Folder 472)
    - Notes on layout, undated (Box 12:, Folder 473)
  - A Moon or a Button [notes, tss, sketches], undated (Box 12, Folder 473a)
  - ["Mr. Littleguy and the Laundry"] (unpublished)
    - Typescript A, undated (Box 12:, Folder 474)
    - Typescript B.1, original sent to Harper and Brothers, ca. 1947 July (Box 12:, Folder 475)
    - Readers' response from Harper and Brothers, 1947 (Box 12:, Folder 476)
    - Typescript B.2, copy sent to Simon and Schuster, ca. 1947 June (Box 12:, Folder 477)
    - Typescript B.3, revised version, ca. 1947 (Box 12:, Folder 478)
    - Typescript C and copy, ca. 1947 (Box 12:, Folder 479)
    - Submission to Parents Magazine and response, 1970 (Box 12:, Folder 479a)
  - Lynnie's Panda (unpublished)
    - Notes, undated (Box 12:, Folder 479b)
    - "Original Draught" and copies, undated (Box 12:, Folder 479c)
    - First dummy, undated (Box 12:, Folder 479d)
  - "New Words for Old" (unpublished)
    - Notes and illustrations, undated (Box 12:, Folder 480)
    - typescripts and manuscripts, undated (Box 12:, Folder 481)
  - Open House for Butterflies
    - Notes, undated (Box 13:, Folder 482)
    - List of proposed titles, undated (Box 13:, Folder 483)
    - Undated manuscripts (Box 13:, Folder 484)
    - Partial typescripts, undated (Box 13:, Folder 485)
    - ["Baby sayings"] [mss], undated (Box 13:, Folder 486)
    - "Rough List" [tss and copy], undated (Box 13:, Folder 487)
    - Manuscripts, ca. 1959 June 5 (Box 13:, Folder 488)
    - Manuscript with layout notes, 1959 September 20 (Box 13:, Folder 489)
    - Manuscript, [1959] October 29 (Box 13:, Folder 490)
    - Typescript with printer's instructions, undated (Box 13:, Folder 491)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 13:, Folder 492)
    - Long layout dummy and copies, undated (Box 13:, Folder 493)
    - Layout sketches, 1958 May 26 (Box 13:, Folder 494)
    - Layout sketch, 1959 March 15 (Box 13:, Folder 495)
    - Undated typescript (Box 13:, Folder 495a)
    - Layout sketches, ca. 1959 June 15 (Box 13:, Folder 496)
    - Layout plan, 1959 July 23 (Box 13:, Folder 497)
    - Layout sketch and list, 1969 September 24 (Box 13:, Folder 498)
    - Layout sketch, undated (Box 13:, Folder 499)
    - Small dummies, undated (Box 13:, Folder 500)
    - Galleys, undated (Box OS:, Folder 660)
    - Play by Laurence Sacharow, undated (Box 13:, Folder 501)
    - Prgrams for musical play, undated (Box 13:, Folder 502)
  - Outline of a simple anthropology book for children, undated (Box 13:, Folder 503)
  - "Potatoes" (unpublished) [mss and sketches], undated (Box 13:, Folder 503a)
  - Posters for children with text by Krauss, undated (Box OS:, Folder 664)
  - ["Princess'] (unpublished) [tss], undated (Box 13:, Folder 503b)
  - Promotional posters, undated (Box OS:, Folder 662)
  - "Puzzles" (unpublished) [illustrations and notes], undated (Box 13:, Folder 504)
  - "Questions" (unpublished) [illustrated mss fragments], undated (Box 13:, Folder 505)
  - "Rock and Sun and Flowers" (unpublished) [tss and mss], undated (Box 13:, Folder 506)
  - ["Rockabye"] (unpublished)
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 13:, Folder 507)
    - Early versions [tss], undated (Box 13:, Folder 508)
    - Partial typescripts, undated (Box 13:, Folder 509)
    - Typescript A, undated (Box 13:, Folder 510)
    - Typescript B, undated (Box 13:, Folder 511)
    - Typescript C, undated (Box 13:, Folder 512)
  - Round and Round (unpublished) [color dummy and copy], undated (Box 13:, Folder 512a)
  - "Short Tall Tale" [tss], undated (Box 13:, Folder 512b)
  - Small Black Lambs Wandering in Red Poppies (unpublished)
    - Contents list for collection, undated (Box 13:, Folder 513)
    - "The Earth is in Love," early verions, undated (Box 13:, Folder 514)
    - Manuscript and typescript fragments, undated (Box 13:, Folder 515)
    - Partial typescript for collection, undated (Box 13:, Folder 516)
    - Typescript for collection A, undated (Box 13:, Folder 517)
    - Typescript for collection B, "Love Poems for Children,", undated (Box 13:, Folder 518)
    - Typescript for collection C, undated (Box 13:, Folder 519)
    - Typescript for collection D, One Dozen Love Poems for Children, undated (Box 13:, Folder 520)
    - Typescript for collection E, undated (Box 13:, Folder 521)
    - Typescript for collection F, undated (Box 13:, Folder 521a)
    - Typescript for collection G, 1982 (Box 13:, Folder 521b)
    - Partial typescript of picture book, undated (Box 13:, Folder 522)
    - Typescripts for picture book, undated (Box 13:, Folder 523)
    - Typescript for picture book, "Poems for Little Clowns,", undated (Box 13:, Folder 524)
    - Arrangement notes for picture book, undated (Box 13:, Folder 525)
    - Picture book dummies, undated (Box 13:, Folder 526)
  - "Some Fine Day" [sketches], undated (Box 14:, Folder 527)
  - Somebody Else's Nut Tree
    - Notes, undated (Box 14:, Folder 528)
    - "Birthday" [tss], undated (Box 14:, Folder 529)
    - "A Girl at a Party" [tss], undated (Box 14:, Folder 530)
    - "The Little Queen" [tss], undated (Box 14:, Folder 531)
    - "Love Song to Elephants" [copy], undated (Box 14:, Folder 532)
    - Partial typescripts, undated (Box 14:, Folder 533)
    - "Unfinal version" [tss], ca. 1957 (Box 14:, Folder 534)
    - "Original Manuscript,", ca. 1957 (Box 14:, Folder 535)
    - Arrangement notes, undated (Box 14:, Folder 536)
    - Sketches by Krauss [originals and copies], undated (Box 14:, Folder 537)
    - Illustrations by Maurice Sendak [copies], undated (Box 14:, Folder 538)
    - Oversize illustrations by Maurice Sendak [copies], undated (Box 18:, Folder 652)
    - "Birthday" and copy, undated (Box 14:, Folder 539)
    - "Birthday" dummy with illustrations by Maurice Sendak and loose dummy pages, undated (Box 14:, Folder 540)
    - Paste-up extras, undated (Box 14:, Folder 541)
    - Paste-up layout, undated (Box 17:, Folder 542)
    - Layout dummy template, undated (Box 17:, Folder 642)
    - Photocopied illustrations [negative], ca. 1958 January 27 (Box 14:, Folder 543)
    - Corrections, undated (Box 14:, Folder 544)
    - Proofs, ca. 1958 (Box 14:, Folder 545)
    - Cut book jacket, ca. 1958 (Box 14:, Folder 546)
    - Promotional materials, 1958, 1985 (Box 14:, Folder 547)
  - Somebody Spilled the Sky
    - "B Ballet" [tss and copies], undated (Box 14:, Folder 547a)
    - "littlekid opera" [tss, mss, copies, sketches], undated (Box 14:, Folder 547b)
    - "Poem" ["Somebody spilled the sky"] [tss], undated (Box 14:, Folder 548)
    - Poem ["Somebody spilled the sky"] dummy, undated (Box 14:, Folder 549)
    - "Song and Act" [tss and mss], undated (Box 14:, Folder 549a)
    - "When I First Saw" [tss], undated (Box 14:, Folder 549b)
    - Partial typescript, undated (Box 14:, Folder 550)
    - Typescript and notes, undated (Box 14:, Folder 550a)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 14:, Folder 551)
    - Oversize sketch, undated (Box 18:, Folder 653)
    - Layout sketch, undated (Box 14:, Folder 552)
    - Proofs, 1979 (Box 14:, Folder 553)
    - Page proofs, 1979 (Box OS:, Folder 665)
    - Catalog, 1979 (Box 14:, Folder 554)
    - Reviews, undated (Box 14:, Folder 555)
  - "Spring Song", [See also "Spring Song" in The Cantilever Rainbow in series VIII.]
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 14:, Folder 556)
    - Layout sketches, undated (Box 14:, Folder 557)
    - Loose dummy pages, undated (Box 14:, Folder 558)
  - "Story of a Mouse and its Friend" [mss], undated (Box 14:, Folder 559)
  - "Story without an End" [mss], undated (Box 14:, Folder 560)
  - "Stuart and Vic" [mss], undated (Box 14:, Folder 561)
  - This Thumbprint
    - Title page, undated (Box 14:, Folder 562)
    - Annotated typescript and copy, undated (Box 14:, Folder 563)
    - Typescripts, ca. 1966-1967 (Box 14:, Folder 564)
    - Rejected texts [tss], undated (Box 14:, Folder 565)
    - Page list (and revisions?), undated (Box 14:, Folder 566)
    - Printer's typescript and annotated copy, 1967 January (Box 14:, Folder 567)
    - Miniature sketches [4 sets], undated (Box 14:, Folder 568)
    - Large sketches, ca. 1966-1967 (Box 14:, Folder 569)
    - Unused sketches, undated (Box 15:, Folder 570)
    - Partial dummies, undated (Box 15:, Folder 571)
    - Partial dummy, ca. 1967 January (Box 15:, Folder 572)
    - Loose dummy pages, undated (Box 15:, Folder 573)
    - Paste-up dummy, undated (Box 15:, Folder 574)
    - Large paste-up dummy, undated (Box 17:, Folder 643)
    - Galley, 1966 December (Box OS:, Folder 661)
    - Cover designs by Krauss, 1964 March (Box 15:, Folder 575)
    - Cut galley page, ca. 1967 January (Box 15:, Folder 576)
    - Mechanicals, undated (Box 18:, Folder 654)
  - Twenty Love Poems for Children [tss and copies], undated (Box 15:, Folder 577)
  - "The Ugly Squareling" [tss], undated (Box 15:, Folder 577a)
  - Unidentified Children's Works I: Materials from envelope, undated (Box 15:, Folder 578)
  - Unidentified Children's Works II: Loose materials, undated (Box 15:, Folder 579)
  - Unidentified illustrations by Krauss: "Boo!" and associated drawings, undated (Box 15:, Folder 580)
  - Unidentified illustrations by Krauss: "Portrait of the Artist", undated (Box 15:, Folder 581)
  - Unidentified illustrations by Krauss: Sketches, undated (Box 15, Folder 582)
  - Unidentified illustrations by others: Maurice Sendak, undated (Box 15:, Folder 583)
  - Unidentified illustrations by others: unknown artists, undated (Box 15:, Folder 584)
  - Unidentified illustrations by others, oversize, undated (Box 17:, Folder 645)
  - Unidentified layout sketches, undated (Box 15:, Folder 585)
  - Unidentified layout sketches, oversize, undated (Box 18:, Folder 655)
  - Unidentified color dummies, large, undated (Box 15:, Folder 586)